We started production of
3rd Girls' Fighter Wing this year.
（あおい）
今年の頭から
制作に入った
「第三飛行少女隊」
We have three weeks until the final episode airs.
最終話放映まで
あと３週間
I'm counting on you all to help see this through!
皆さんの力を
どうか貸してください！
Yeah!
（太郎(たろう)）しゃ～っす！
（スタッフ）はい！
Now, let's make sure the finale ends on a high note.
（丸川(まるかわ)）
それでは最終話納品を目指して
All units scramble!
全機 スクランブル！
Yay!
A Delivery Too Far Away
3rd Girls' Fighter Wing #13
Schedule (the new 100 cuts)
December
After re-editing, how many cuts does this final episode have?
（あおい）
再編集して 最終話
トータル
何カットになったっけ？
500 cuts.
（佐藤(さとう)）
５００カットです
There'll probably be around 10,000 tween frames.
予想動画枚数
１万枚いきそうです
10,000...
１万枚…
What's the status on the 400 cuts we started already?
先行してる400カットの
内訳は？
Keyframes are done for 320 of them.
190 of those have passed the AD check too.
（安藤(あんどう)）
原画アップが320カット
そのうち 作監アップが190
40 are at the ED, and 90 are at the AD for checks now.
演出チェックと作監チェック中が
それぞれ40と90です
Got it.
了解です
Plan and map out the scheduling to ensure work on the new cuts
先行カットと
新作カットの動きが
土壇場で重ならないよう
doesn't overlap with the other 400.
前もってシミュレーション
しといてください
（佐藤･安藤）
はい
Okay.
For the remaining keyframe cuts, of which there are...
それから まだ上がってない
原画の… え～と…
80 cuts.
80カット
Keep a close watch on those too.
それも しっかり
追っかけてください
We can do this!
追っかけましょう！
Yeah!
（佐藤･安藤）
はい！
Two weeks left, huh?
（堂本(どうもと)）
う～ん あと２週間か
I could look at 400 or 500 frames a day if I had to.
頑張って 一日
４００～５００枚かな
So you could handle up to 7,000 tweens, right?
堂本さんが
目を通せる動画は
７,０００枚って
とこでしょうか
What should we do about the other 3,000?
となると
残り３,０００枚は…
Wait, there's seriously going to be 10,000?!
（堂本）
えっ 待って
１万枚もいくの？
Most likely.
予想では…
3,000 outsourced tweens and coloring?
3,000枚 動仕まきか
I'm sorry.
（安藤）
すみません
We don't have a choice.
しゃあない　動画まく前に
私のところに持ってきて
Send them to me before you submit to tweening.
I'll add guides for mid-motion frames.
中割りの参考にあたり入れるから
If the tween frames are off,
everything bounces around.
（堂本）
動画が崩れると
ぷるんぷるんしちゃうからね
Some guides should help prevent that.
参考に あたりを入れるってこと
It's kind of like risk hedging.
それでリスクヘッジ
Come on, take a day off.
（新川(しんかわ)）
え～ そりゃ休まないと
休め休め
You totally should.
But we'll be busy like crazy around Christmas, right?
（花巻）
でも ちょうどクリスマスが
作業のヤマですよね
A thousand frames a day is—
一日1,000枚って…
All the more reason to go on that date now!
（新川）
だから
その前にデートやっとけって話
You cheeky little princess. Go on and steal his heart!
この幸せもんが～
決めてきちゃいな
Can it be done on time?
（スタッフ）間に合うんですかね
（佐倉(さくら)）間に合わせるよ
It has to be.
We need the resources to work with, though.
（佐倉）
もちろん　積まれればね
Ah, I also made a new plugin.
あと新しいプラグイン
作ってみたんだよね
（スタッフ）
えっ…
この期に及んで またですか
Again? This far in?
It adds a glassy texture with just a click!
ガラスのハイライトが
一発で出るんだよ
No....
（渥美(あつみ)）
違う
This is wrong.
こうじゃない
Nakagaito, you have models for the MiG-21, right?
（下柳(しもやなぎ)）
中垣内(なかがいと) お前 ミグ21持ってたよな？
We do, but it's low-poly, so only 10,000 polygons.
（中垣内）
持ってますけど ローポリで
１万ポリゴンぐらいしかないですよ
I've got a little request for you.
（下柳）
相談だけど
それを20万ポリゴンぐらい上げつつ
Could you make that 200,000 and update it to a MiG-21S?
更に ミグ21Ｓに
モデリング修正できない？
That includes the textures as well, right?
（中垣内）
えっ… それって
テクスチャ貼り込みもですよね？
（下柳）
うん １週間で頼む
Yeah. In a week, please.
That's asking a lot...
え～ またムチャな…　あっ
Well... We can handle it.
まあ できなくはないですけど
I'll do Tatiana. I've worked on her cuts from start to finish.
（内田(うちだ)）
私はタチアナやります
ずっとつきあってきたキャラなんで
Super effect master, you'll do the part where it's shot down?
（井口(いぐち)）
スーパーエヘクター
撃墜シーンやりますよね？
（遠藤(えんどう)）
えっ？　まあ やるのは当然として
Of course I'll do it, but I'd rather you not call me that.
その呼び方 イヤなんですけど
There's one cut I'd like you to let me do.
（絵麻(えま)）
あの… 私
どうしても やらせてもらいたい
カットがあるんですけど
Which one?
（井口）
えっ どこ？
Lucy's.
ルーシーの…
But you also have AD work...
（安藤）
えっ でも安原さん 作監の仕事も…
I'll take care of that too.
そっちも ちゃんとやります
I won't delay it. No matter what.
絶対 遅らせませんから ぜひ…
Please let me do it!
どうか やらせてください！
It should be fine.
（小笠原(おがさわら)）よろしいと思います
（井口）うん
You want to do Texas too, Kunogin?
（井口）
クノギンもやる？　テキサスのとこ
I'll do it!
や… るます！
On to the calf then...
Aria nervous
Calf approaching
It comes close and
opens its mouth
high-angle lens effect
A bit surprised,
Aria gives
it milk
Lucy watches,
smiling
Aria smiles
Lucy gives it milk too
It raises its head
to follow the milk bottle
Wags tail
Aria watches
Lucy looks at Aria,
urges her with her eyes
（井口）
したら 子牛は…
I haven't done a cow since Amazon Shirobeko.
（杉江(すぎえ)）
牛は「アマゾン白べこ」以来だな
I'd like to see some real cows to use as reference.
ちょっと本物の牛を
取材してみたい気がするけど
I'll look into it!
（みどり）
今すぐ調べます！
That's Team Emacchi for you.
“チーム絵麻っち”だね
Move your things, please.
（瀬川(せがわ)）
荷物どけてもらっていい？
Just a sec.
ちょっと待て　ん？
What? It's rude to stare, you know.
（瀬川）
何よ 失礼ね
I... uh...
あっ いや…
I'm working here until we finish. Howdy, neighbor.
これからアップまで
スタジオ入りするから
（瀬川）よろしく
（遠藤）え～！　あっ…
Here, when Lucy runs,
（絵麻）
ここのルーシーの走りですが
should there be frames where she's completely airborne?
空中ポーズ
入れたほうがいいですか？
It should be a really energetic sprint against the wind.
（木下(きのした)）
そうだね
向かい風の中
いても立ってもみたいな走り
And make her hair flip around boldly once she stops running.
立ち止まってからも
髪の毛 強めになびかせたい
Okay.
はい
Do you have any other questions?
（山田(やまだ)）
他に質問は？
Wi...
Wi?
Windspeedishowfast?
…うそく 何メートルですか？
Winspihow...
うそくな…？
Ah, the wind speed?
（円(まどか)）
あっ 風速ですか！
Quite strong, about 5 meters per second!
風速は やや強めの５メートルです
メイビーです
Maybe!
Andou, you take ages to add peg holes.
The sun's gonna set before you're done!
（太郎）
んだよ アンドゥーのタップ貼り
とれえな　日が暮れちゃうよ
（安藤）
うう～ すみません
I'm sorry!
Yours are off though. Redo.
（矢野(やの)）
お前こそズレてるだろ　やり直し
They should be fine as long as the lines are about right!
センターが合ってりゃ
ノープロブレムっすよ
How about you just redo them?
（矢野）
全然ノーじゃないだろ
Nitpicker.
細かいっすね　大事なのはスピード
Speed's what matters.
What sorcery is that, Dai-chan?
それ何やってんの 大(だい)ちゃん
This is nothing.
Apologies for calling again.
（平岡(ひらおか)）
別に…
I'm Satou from Musashino Animation.
武蔵野(むさしの)アニメーションの
佐藤でございます
Please call me back when you get home.
お帰りになったら
一度 お電話いただけますか？
Thank you in advance.
よろしくお願いいたします
Who was that?
何 誰？
Tanokura-san.
田之倉(たのくら)さんです
He ran away.
（太郎）逃げたな
（佐藤）えっ？
Isn't Tanokura-san working at ATAX now,
（平岡）
田之倉さんなら
アタクスに入ってんじゃないの
helping with that movie?
劇場版の追い込みで
He's supposed to be juggling that and 3rd Wing.
今は うちとそっちの
掛け持ちのはずだから
Should I ask someone I know about keyframe progress?
知り合いに原画アップいつか
聞いてみようか
（あおい）
あっ… ありがとうございます
Yes, please do!
Thank you so much, Hiraoka-san!
ありがとうございます 平岡さん
It's no big deal.
ん… 別に…
What are you looking at?
あっ なんだよ
Nothing.
別に
Rii-chan, can you get me references on landing gear?
（美沙(みさ)）
りーちゃん 引き込み脚の
参考画像って手に入るかな？
No worries if you can't—I can do it myself.
無理だったら
こっちでなんとかするけど
There's a specialty bookstore in Ikebukuro.
I can look it up tomorrow.
（みどり）
いや 池袋(いけぶくろ)に専門の書店があるんで
あした中に調べて送ります
Later, Mii-chan-senpai!
お疲れっす みーちゃん先輩
This smell brings back memories.
懐かしいな このにおい
You kept farm animals?
（絵麻）
飼ってたんですか？
My uncle did.
おじさんがね
Cattle and people were much closer back then.
昔は もっと
家畜との距離が近かったから
As were life and death.
命と死の距離も
I wonder if Lucy feels that way too.
ルーシーも そうなんでしょうか
Hey, stop that!
こら～ 牛め！　このベコめ！
You naughty heifer!
We won't use you for reference if you pull any more stunts like that!
そういうことすると
参考にしてやんないからね
（ルーシー）
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Sorry! Are you Aria-san?
あの もしかして やっぱり
ありあさん？
Thank you, Aria-san!
（ルーシー）
ありがとう ありあさん
I'm now one step closer to my dream!
今 私…
Lucy
少しだけ夢に近づきました！
Prussia
Studio
Really? Does it seem that tough looking back on it?
（永井(ながい)）
えっ そう？
端から見たら
そんなに重労働に見える？
Prince of Baseball
TV Anime
I couldn't feel it at all.
全然 自覚ないけどな
The manager's always in the back, looking after everyone, right?
（しずか）
マネージャーって
裏方っていうか
お世話係でしょ
Girl C
Isn't that tough?
大変じゃない？
Manager
Sure, it's not easy,
（永井）
まあ そうだけどね
Manager
but seeing them all practice really fires me up!
みんなが
練習 頑張ってるのを見ると
私も元気もらえるんだ
I see! That would make someone happy!
そっか そういう喜びもあるんだ
Fresh boxed meals
Sakaitei
Here is your order. It will be 4,730 yen.
（店員）
お待ちどおさま
4,730円になります
Please bill it to Musashino Animation.
（みどり）
“武蔵野アニメーション”で
領収書 お願いします
Boldly, but carefully.
（丸川）
大胆に しかし細心に
Stew and anime are the same.
おでんもアニメも同じだねえ
3rd Girls' Fighter Wing
Here they come!
（ノア）来るぞ！
（タチアナ･クリスティーネ）はい
Roger.
You're going overboard again.
（稲浪(いななみ)）
ま～たムチャやって
Will this make airtime?
（稲浪）これ 放映 間に合うの？
（葛城(かつらぎ)）えっ？
At this point, we can just push it back four or five times!
まあ こうなりゃ
３度落とすも４度落とすも同じ！
No, you can't!
（葛城）おい～！
（木下）ウソウソ 冗談
I'm kidding!
The director shouldn't say stuff like that!
監督が言うと…
Could you move the start of the BGM to when the dialogue comes in, not the start of the cut?
でさ ＢＧＭの入り
カット頭じゃなくて
セリフ受けにしてくれる？
Sure.
（山渕(やまぶち)）
はい
（ｽﾋﾟｰｶｰ:鳥の鳴き声）
（木下）あれ？　この声 何？
What's that sound?
A mockingbird. I mean, they're in Texas.
（大山(おおやま)）
マネシツグミ
テキサスだから入れてみました
Can't just have crows, right?
カラスじゃ変でしょ
They didn't even last 15 minutes.
（タチアナ）
15分も たたなかったなんてね
The enemy has definitely gotten stronger.
（クリスティーネ）
敵が強力になったのは…
In cut 47, I heard her say,
"They didn't even last 15 minutes,"
カット47 “15分も たたなかった”
って聞こえるんですけど
We can't just—
but the line is, "They didn't even have 15 minutes."
セリフは
“15分 もたなかった”なんですよ
They didn't even last 15 minutes.
（タチアナ）
15分も たたなかったなんてね
（木下たち）あっ！
（葛城）マズい！
Oh no! This is terrible!
That changes the meaning!
全然 意味が違ってきますね
誤植だ！　ごめん アフレコの時
気が付かなかった
It's a typo! I didn't notice at recording!
Yamaguchi-kun, can you fix it?
山渕君 直せる？
They didn't even last 15 minutes.
（タチアナ）
15分も たたなかったなんてね
How's this?
これでどうだ
They didn't even have 15 minutes.
15分 もたなかったなんてね
（一同）おお～！
（木下）さすがプロ！
Like a real pro!
Aw, shucks.
何言ってるんですか
All right!
お～し！
Who did this cut?
このカット 誰？
あっ！　うう～ すみ…
I'm sor—
（木下）
いいね～ ルーシーとありあ
Lucy and Aria here look great!
Holy Mother of God.
（山田）
聖母だな 八千草(やちぐさ)薫(かおる)的な
Reminds me of Yachigusa Kaoru.
No way Kunogi-san knows who that is.
いや 久乃木さん 知らないでしょ
They're saying you did a great job!
褒められてるよ 久乃木さん
うっ…
あ… りがとうございます！
Thank... you very much!
I haven't done keyframes in a while.
I felt a bit rusty doing them.
原画は久しぶりだったので
衰えを感じました
Come on. No saying that for another 40 years.
衰えなんて40年早いよ
My apologies.
失礼いたしました
Emacchi's lines have started
looking like yours, Segawa-san.
絵麻っち
瀬川さんの線に似てきましたよ
えっ？　私は井口さんに
似てきたと思ってたんだけど
I thought they'd started resembling yours.
フフフ　なんにせよ
先行き楽しみっすね
Either way, I look forward to seeing her keep developing!
I'll be back right away!
（木佐(きさ)）
すぐ戻ってくるんで
興津(おきつ)さん ホントのホント
I promise, Okitsu-san!
So give back my saddle and pedals!
だから サドルとシートポストを…
We can just send Takanashi instead.
（興津）
高梨(たかなし)に行かせましょうか
You called?
（太郎）
なんすか～？
Day of Delivery
Roll 18 has arrived. I'll swap it into place.
（オペレーター）
はい ロール18が届きました
順番に差し替えま～す
Okay!
（木下）
はい！
Three locations in the Tokyo area, Hokkaido, Hiroshima, and Kobe.
（葛城）
首都圏３か所 北海道 広島 神戸
それから…
Then also...
Nabe-chan, the three of us won't be enough to handle this!
ちょっとナベちゃん
この３人じゃ届けられないよ
Miyamori, you'll have to take the on-air tape to the station.
宮森(みやもり) オンエアテープ
局に持ってってもらうからな
はい！
Sure thing!
（葛城）
問題は上高地(かみこうち)
Delivery list
Odawara Broadcasting
Nanbo TV            Kobe TV 4
Asahiyama Penguin Broadcasting         TV Sado
Hiroshima Bunta Broadcasting    TV Kami-Kouchi
The issue is Kami-Kouchi! What do we do?
どうすんの？
That's pretty far from the
Matsumoto Interchange too.
（水山）
あそこ
松本(まつもと)インターから遠いんだよな
ダメだ～！
We're doomed!
（渡辺(わたなべ)）
撮影 あとどれくらいかかりそう？
When will filming be completed?
Before noon.
昼前には…
Noon?! Then we can't deliver it by evening!
昼前って！
ああ～ 夕方までには間に合わない
放送 落ちる～！
We won't make it in time for the airing!
（水山）
ちょっと 縁起でもない
Come on, man, don't say that.
We've got no choice. Time to use our wild card.
（渡辺）
しかたない
ワイルドカードを出します
Any problems, director?
（オペレーター）
監督 何か
No, this should be fine.
うっ…　いや これで大丈夫です
お疲れさまでした
Thank you very much!
Thank you!
（一同）
お疲れさまでした！
Hello? This is Miyamori.
もしもし 宮森です
Editing is done. We're done.
Ｖ編 終わりました　完パケです
You can let the staff—
スタッフ バラしちゃって…
（携帯電話から聞こえる歓声）
みゃーもりん お疲れさま！
Thanks so much, Meowmori!
Thanks for all your hard work!
いろいろ支えてくれて
ありがとね！
I'm so sorry for all the trouble!
いえ こちらこそ！
ご迷惑かけてすみませんでした
本日 打ち上げ会場
クルクルクルーズですよ
The party will be held at Cool Crew!
Be sure to come by!
皆さん お忘れなく！
タダ酒 ヤッホ～イ！
It's happening!
興津さんから これ預かってます
Okitsu-san entrusted this to me.
Thank you.
あっ どうも
Good job.
お疲れ
You too, Segawa-san.
アハッ　いや 瀬川さんこそ
Thank you.
お疲れさまでした
Likewise.
ご苦労さまでした
ふんっ ふんっ ふんっ
Okay!
よっしゃ～！
This is Miyamori.
（あおい）
あっ 宮森です
矢野さん 今 どちらですか？
Where are you, Yano-san?
Right here!
There you are!
（あおい）
お疲れさまです！
Katsuragi-san, Kobe TV 4.
（渡辺）
じゃあ 葛城さん 神戸ヨンテレ
おう！
Yeah!
Hokkaido Asahiyama Penguin Broadcasting.
（渡辺）
北海道旭川(あさひかわ)ペンギン放送
Yup-yup.
Niigata, TV Sado.
（渡辺）新潟テレビ佐渡(さど)
（矢野）はい
Yes.
Hiroshima, Bunta Broadcasting.
（渡辺）広島 文太(ぶんた)放送
（あおい）はい！
Roger!
I'll handle Tokyo NX, Odawara Broadcasting,
and Nanbo Channel.
で 俺がＴＯＫＹＯ ＮＸと
小田原(おだわら)ＴＶと南房(なんぼう)チャンネル
What about TV Kami-Kouchi?
あれ？　上高地テレビは？
あっ… 興津さん！
Okitsu-san!
The on-air tape, please.
オンエアテープ
You don't need a navigator?
（渡辺）
ナビなしで大丈夫ですか？
I know the way.
（興津）
“勝手知ったる”よ
Godspeed to all of you.
幸運を祈る！
Ready,
レディー
go!
（葛城）
ハァ ハァ…
ハァ ハァ… あ～ 待って待って
Wait for me!
See you! Good luck!
（矢野）
じゃあね 頑張って
You too!
（あおい）
はい 矢野さんも！
（警告のブザー）
えっ！　何？　なんでなの～！
Why? Why'd it go off?!
Oh, right.
あっ そっか
Don't fall asleep!
（ミムジー）
寝るな！　寝たら落ちるぞ
いろんな意味で
Do that and you'll fall in more ways than one!
If you oversleep and go all the way to Hakata, you won't make it.
（ロロ）
寝過ごして
博多(はかた)まで行っちゃったら
間に合わないよ
Pull it together!
（ロロ）ほらほら 見て見て
（ミムジー）ほら しっかり！
I know! I got this!
大丈夫よ 分かってる
（衝撃音）
ひい～！
No! Save the tape! Just save the tape!
テープは… テープだけは！
Nanbo Channel
Look, it's snow!
（ロロ）ほら 雪だよ 雪
（ミムジー）降ってる！
It's snowing!
It really is!
ホントだ
Attention, all passengers.
（車内アナウンス）
お客様に お知らせいたします
Because of inclement weather, this train will be proceeding on a delayed schedule.
天候の影響で
徐行運転をさせていただきます
I've got no time for this!
（男）
なんだよ こんな時に
天候の影響で
徐行運転をさせていただきます
（女の子）
足 痛いよ
My back hurts!
It better not take all night.
We apologize for the inconvenience at this busy time.
（学生）
まさか夜明かし？
お急ぎのところ
大変申し訳ありません
We do short distances!
Sightseeing/Rental OK!
I can't fail this far in!
こんなところで
くたばってたまるか～！
TV 4
（葛城）テープ…
（受付嬢）うわ～！
I've brought 3rd Girls' Fighter Wing!
「第三飛行少女隊」最終話
ただ今 到着いたしました！
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Odawara Broadcasting
TV Kami-Kouchi
We have received the delivery of above product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
We have received the delivery of above product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
We have received the delivery of above product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
We have received the delivery of above product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
We have received the delivery of above product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
We have received the delivery of above product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
We have received the delivery of above product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
We have received the delivery of above product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
We have received the delivery of above product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
We have received the delivery of above product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Here. Thank you very much.
We have received the delivery of above product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
（受付）
はい ご苦労さまでした
We have received the delivery of above product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
In charge:
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
In charge:
Company                    Kami-Kouchi Television Inc.
Production Department
Media Team
Awa Kamonji
Receipt
We have received the delivery of the product.
In charge:
If you'll excuse me, then.
（興津）
それでは失礼いたします
Please take care.
お気をつけて
License and registration.
（服部(はっとり)）
免許証 名前
Okitsu Yuka. I'm in animation production.
興津由佳(ゆか) アニメーション制作
You were 7 kilometers over the limit.
７キロ オーバーだ
It's been 8 years, speed limit goddess.
８年ぶりだな 音速の貴婦人
Long time no see, Hattori-san.
お久しぶりです 服部さん
I see you've since been promoted.
警部に昇進なさったんですね
Excuse me, how long will this take?
あの… あとどれくらい
かかりますか？
The town's crowded because of all the year-end events.
（運転手）
う～ん 今 年末で
いろんなイベントやってるんで
混むんだよな～
Could I get off here?
あの！
ここで降ろしてもらっていいですか
Here? But it's still—
（運転手）
えっ？　いいけど まだ…
走ります！
I'll run!
（あおい）
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Run! Run!
走れ走れ！
You're almost there!
あとちょっと
Run like this!
こう走るんだよ　うお～！
What do I really want to do?
（あおい）
私 何がしたいのかな？
I'll do anything!
なんでもやります！
I don't know where I should start.
（あおい）
何からやればいいのか分からなくて
Anime's all about the motion!
アニメって
やっぱり動きだと思った
I want to work on something with a story!
ストーリーのある作品に
ＣＧで参加したいんです
In my case, I need stories.
自分には物語が必要なんす
Go in confident and determined.
自信を持て 覚悟をしろ
I...
私は…
Hiroshima Bunta Broadcasting
（ロロ･ミムジー）
来た～！
We're here!
Go-go-go!
（ミムジー）いけいけ～！
（ロロ）頑張れ 頑張れ～！
Keep it up!
3rd Girls' Fighter Wing
Thank you for the on-air tape.
（プロデューサー）
オンエアテープ
確かに受け取りました
3rd Girls' Fighter Wing
Sorry for the trouble caused!
（あおい）
ご迷惑をおかけして
本当にすみませんでした！
Not at all. Thanks for coming all this way.
こちらこそ わざわざ遠いところを
ありがとうございました
It's in your care now!
どうかよろしくお願いします！
Yes, indeed.
はい それは確かに
Phew, I'm so tired.
（ミムジー）
はあ～ 疲れた
But now it's finally over.
（ロロ）うんしょっと
（ミムジー）終わった 終わった
It's not over. This is just the beginning.
終わってないよ これからだよ
これからどうしたいのか決まった？
Have you figured out what you want to do now?
Do you want to keep making anime? If so, why?
このままアニメを作りたいのか
作りたいとしたら なぜなのか
Well, now I have time to take it easy and think about it.
う～んと…
これから ゆっくり考える
No slacking!
甘ったれんな～！
The time for focusing only on the next task at hand has passed.
目先のことばかり考えてる時期は
もう終わりだよ
Lolo! Lolo's gone loco!
（ミムジー）
ロロが…
ロロが変になっちゃった
I'm fine!
変じゃない！
Now you should climb up high and look far out.
そろそろ 少し高いところから
遠くを見る時が来たんだよ
Climb up high... and look far out...
少し高い… 遠く…
I like making anime, and I like the people who make anime.
アニメを作ることが好きだし
アニメを作る人が好きだから
I want to keep making anime!
私 これからもずっと
アニメを作り続けたい！
Right. Good for you.
うん よし！
I'd like to start now. Is that okay?
皆さん そろそろ始めたいと
思いますが大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
（男性１）お前こそ大丈夫か？
（男性２）眼鏡 割れてんぞ～
Your glasses are broken!
Thanks to all your efforts, the final episode was delivered without issues.
（葛城）
おかげさまをもちまして―
最終話納品 無事完了しました
（拍手）
I'd like director Kinoshita to say a few words to commemorate the occasion.
（葛城）
打ち上げに際しまして
まず木下監督より
ひと言 頂きたいと思います
Me? Out of the blue?!
えっ？　俺 いきなり～？
いいけどさ 何も考えてないよ～
I-I don't really mind, but I haven't prepared a speech.
H-Hello!
こ… こんばんは
監督の木下誠一です
I'm the director, Kinoshita Seiichi.
We know!
（大山）知ってる！
（稲浪）早く飲ませろ！
Let us drink already!
You're already drinking.
…って もう飲んでるし
じ… 自分で言うのも なんですが
It's a bit weird to say this myself,
but I think that 3rd Wing turned out great.
「サンジョ」は
すごくいい作品になったと思います
Right?
思うよね？
Huh? Right.
（藤）
えっ？　ああ はい
Aria will continue flying, and so will we.
え～ これからも
ありあは飛び続けるわけで
それは僕らも同じなわけで
My only hope is for us to meet again, in those skies.
いつか再び どこかの空で
会えるといいな～
My wife...
奥さんとも… なんて…
（あおい）
すみません 遅れま… うっ！
Sorry, I'm la—
お～！ それでは 将来 ムサニを
しょって立つデスクの宮森あおいが
So let's all ask the great pillar of Musani's future,
production manager Miyamori Aoi, to give a toast!
乾杯の音頭を
務めさせていただきます！
Go ahead.
挨拶
What?! No way! Why me?!
そんな！　私なんかが…
Yes way. Now get up there, ace.
“そんな”じゃない
ほら いけ エース
Good evening, everyone. I'm the PM, Miyamori.
えっと 皆さん お疲れさまでした
デスクの宮森です
I, uh... Thank you very much!
あの… え～と…
本当にありがとうございました
I know it sounds stupid,
当たり前のことなんですけど
「サンジョ」に関わってくれた方が
but it surprises me that this many people were involved with 3rd Wing.
こんなに大勢なんだと知って
ビックリしています
Sorry for stating the obvious.
すみません
なんか今更なこと言って
But you wrote the story,
でも 物語を考えたり
キャラクターを描いたり
drew the characters,
made them move,
更に それを生き生きと動かしたり
added your voice, music,
それから 演技や音楽や
もうホント
いろんな人の いろんな力…
and used all your various skills,
your fantastic talents, to complete 3rd Wing.
才能が加わってくださって
「サンジョ」が出来たんですよね
And not just the obvious stuff like that.
そして その直接的な
つながりだけじゃなくて
You also bring in influences from the past,
or from other shows or studios.
間接的なこと
過去からとか
別の作品や会社から
受け継がれてきたこともあるわけで
If we count those too,
それを含めたら 何十万人という人
hundreds of thousands of people and whole decades have added up
何年 何十年という時間が
つぎ込まれて
見てくれる人の感想や思いも
全部 合わさって
with the viewers' emotions and ideas
to create new anime.
アニメは出来上がってるんだなと
It might be just a tiny candle flame,
なんか それって
細いロウソクの火みたいな
ものかもしれないけど
but as we pass that tiny flame on and on,
その小さな火が
次々に受け継がれて
it becomes a flame that will never die out,
永遠に消えることのない炎となって
that will continue to shine over all the world!
世界を照らすものじゃないかって
So,
だから
I think I'd like to keep bringing that light into people's lives in the future too!
これからも ずっと人の心を
明るく照らしていきたいと思います
Thank you very much,
どうもありがとうございました！
and I hope we can work together again!
これからも
よろしくお願いします！
Cheers!
乾杯！
（一同）
Hey Lunar, Lunar!
ne
lu
nar
ne
lu
nar
The stars shine down on us
fu
ri
so
gu
ho
shi
ta
chi
no
hi
ka
ri
ga
as if from beyond the waves of time
i
ma
ko
no
to
ki
no
mo
ja
na
i
yo
u
ni
It's gonna take just a little more
ki
mi
no
mo
to
he
do
ku
ma
de
ni
until I make it to your side, so wait for me
mo
u
su
ko
shi
ka
ru
no
ma
t
te
I've got a present for you behind my back
se
na
ka
ni
ku
shi
ta
p
re
se
n
t
no
ha
ko
I want to surprise you and see you open it
fu
ra
tto
mi
se
ta
i
hi
ra
i
te
ho
shi
i
I want to see your smile
so
no
e
ga
o
mi
ta
i
Hey Lunar, Lunar!
ne
lu
nar
ne
lu
nar
I ran through the night
ma
yo
na
ka
wo
ke
nu
te
ku
Hey Lunar, Lunar!
ne
lu
nar
ne
lu
nar
Slip down on the curve of the moon
mi
ka
zu
ki
su
be
ri
o
te
Hey Lunar, Lunar!
ne
lu
nar
ne
lu
nar
I can't hold back my feelings
o
sa
e
ki
re
na
i
ko
no
o
mo
i
Hey Lunar, Lunar!
ne
lu
nar
na
ne
lu
nar
na
Just let the light reflect bright
so
no
ma
ki
ra
ri
ha
n
sha
sa
se
te
My glittering platinum jet
ka
ga
ya
ku
no
pla
ti
num
jet
Nabe-chan, the next project's been decided!
ナベちゃん 次の企画 決まったよ
What is it?
（渡辺）
なんすか？
Two Piece.
「ツーピース」
You mean that bandit manga?
えっ？　あの山賊漫画の？
That's a big catch!
大物じゃないっすか
I've got a Kinoshita Seiichi-original project running too.
あっ 木下誠一オリジナル企画も
動かしてるんですけど
Border Town Depopulation Girl.
「限界集落過疎娘」
We're going double line next year then!
じゃあ 来年 ツーラインだ
マジっすか！
Are you serious?
Doesn't it feel funny?
（絵麻）なんか不思議だよね
（しずか）うん
What do you mean?
えっ 何？
The five of us are all here together.
だって ５人そろってるんだよ
ここに
That's right.
あっ そっか
This is only the beginning.
これからだけどね
Especially for the Seven Lucky Warriors.
特に「七福陣」は… っすね
Now I could make Saraswati look much cooler.
今だったら 弁財天
もうちょっとカッコよく描けるかな
In fact, I want to redraw them all!
ううん やっぱり全員 描き直したい
I want to record it again so it sounds more natural!
私も！
もっと自然に聞こえるように
録(と)り直したい
I think I could write the god of longevity's doubts as dialogue much better now.
自分も 寿老人の悩みとか
もうちょいリアルに
セリフにできると思うんす！
Mind taking a look at this?
I remade the treasure boat with CG.
ちょっと見てもらえますか？
宝船 ３Ｄで作ってみたんです
So cool!
カッコいい！
I want to draw in characters!
キャラ のせたい
And we're not too far off from being able to!
のせられますよ 遠くない未来に
Everyone got a donut?
（あおい）
みんな ドーナツ持った？
Yep!
We'll keep...
私たちは
...doing our best...
これからも精いっぱい
...to make great anime.
アニメを作り続けることを
That's our...
誓いま…
...promise!
Don-don-donuts, let's go nuts!
（一同）
ドーナツ ど～んといこう！